SIDDARAMESHWAR B KURI

Frontend Developer

Ph.: - +917829902474

Email: - kurisiddu@gmail.com

Professional summary

An energetic IT professional having 6+ years of experience on website, platform and applications development using Agile (Scrum, KANBAN, Lean) methodologies by leading and working closely with Clients, UX Designers, Solution Architects, BA and QA teams. Hands on experience in working with the different domains like Security, Networking, e-commerce (B2B, B2C) sector; teams across globe especially in Canada, USA, UK and India.

Key skills

- UI
- o Angular 2 and above, AngularJS, TypeScript
- o JavaScript, Advanced JavaScript, OOJS, Handlebars
- O Karma with Mocha, Chai, and Jasmine libraries, Protractor
- o jQuery, HTML5, Bootstrap, CSS3, LESS, SASS
- Others
 - o Accessibility, and Analytics
 - o Cross-browser compatibility, and Responsiveness,
 - o Ajax request/response handling, and Rest API integrations handling
- Version Control
 - o GIT, SVN
- Build Tools
 - o Grunt, Gulf, npm
- Code Quality/Review
 - O Code Collaborator, Sonar, GIT

Academic qualifications

2008-2012. B.E Bachelor of Engineering (Electronics and Communication), RLJ Institute of Technology, Visveswaraya Technological University, IN. WES accredited bachelor's degree.

Trainings and Certifications

2016: JavaScript and OOJS - Argus Electronics Security System Pvt ltd

2017: Angular 2 and above with Typescript – United Technologies Corporation

Work Experience

Chubb Alba Control System Limited

May 2016 – Till Date

Working as a front-end developer and responsible for designing, developing and testing of https://www.utc.com using agile methodologies by following industry wise best practices. Some of the roles and responsibilities are listed below.

Working on frontend efforts for https://www.utc.com website which provides technology products and services to the building systems and aerospace industries worldwide.

- Involved in implementation of below components using Angular 2 with typescript, CSS3, HTML5 and Bootstrap features for https://www.utc.com
 - o Auto play view using carousels feature
 - o Primary and secondary navigators
 - o Search using api/ajax calls
 - o Header, Footer and Body Text component
- Involved in the implementation of responsiveness, cross browser compatibility, accessibility requirements, and analytics requirements
- Ensure the technical feasibility of UI/UX designs
- Implementation of print friendly version of entire site pages across different browsers using print styles
- Analytics requirements are implemented using customized tracking implementation which interacts with adobe
- Involved in the implementation of below pages
 - o News page
 - o Products and Brands pages
 - Social impact pages
- Involved in writing unit test cases for newly designed components using jasmine library.
- Analyze PSD's and wireframe mocks before starting to implement new requirements
- Implementation of session handling for user login and logout using local storage and cookies handling

Argus Electronics Security Systems Pvt Ltd

Sep 2015 – May 2016

Worked as a front-end developer for Honeywell security team and involved in design, development and testing of the https://www.security.honeywell.com/ website. Delivered to the expectations on release basis without compromising the quality by following agile methodologies. Various responsibilities involved are

- Implementation of various components JavaScript, jQuery, CSS3, HTML5, and Bootstrap vue.js and react for Honeywell security site.
- Involved in the implementation of Access Control System product pages like Access control Solutions, Control Panels/Hardware, Visitor Management Systems etc.
- Implemented unit testing with expected code coverage, E2E testing, Responsiveness
- Involved in the implementation of cross browser compatibility, accessibility requirements, and analytics requirements
- Involved in bug fixing, and also A/B testing of the site using internal AB testing framework

Securens Systems Pvt Ltd

Apr 2014 – Sep 2015

Responsible and Accountable for building new age Internet of Things (IoT) http://www.securens.in/ website portal. Some of the roles and responsibilities involved are

- Involved in design, implementation, and bug fixing above website portal
- Development of new user-facing features
- Collaborate with other team members and stakeholders
- Involved in the implementation of responsiveness, cross browser compatibility, accessibility requirements, and analytics requirements
- Utilized bootstrap CSS features for responsiveness and template designing

Honeywell Automation India Pvt Ltd

Dec 2012 – Feb 2014

Responsible for the implementation, bug fixing and maintenance of https://www.honeywell.com/worldwide/en-in/hail automation website using **jQuery**, **JavaScript**, **HTML** and **CSS** features.

- Involved in header, footer and navigation issue fixing
- Designed and developed home page side navigation and latest news side catalog which pulls latest's news always
- Implemented unit testing with expected code coverage, E2E testing, Responsiveness
- Involved in the implementation of cross browser compatibility, accessibility requirements, and analytics requirements